hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah
Kowski and on this podcast we talk about
ways for you to grow in your life in
your business right now I'm traveling uh
with my family and so that's why I'm
filming here at our Airbnb
location um one of the things I wanted
to address here today is something that
I noticed that stops a lot of people
from succeeding is the the fear of
failure and it goes beyond
just you know the something not working
out it really has more to do with our
desire for
control than anything
else and like even as I sit here
thinking about this
podcast um just about an hour ago I was
struggling to come up with what I was
going to talk about in this podcast and
immediately it hit me my own fear of it
not being good enough it not resonating
with people it not connecting was
stopping me from
recording and connecting with people
because I was
concerned
that it might be a waste of time it
might not land
right um and I get caught up in my head
with these thoughts these are old
thoughts that used to come in that quite
frankly I've addressed
previously but I still have to combat
them every time I record a podcast do a
course do a training do really anything
in my business uh to impact people and
and and that fear of failure we have to
address otherwise it will defeat us it
will stop us from even putting ourselves
out there and what it is is the root of
it is not really fear of failure it's
fear of being out of
control it's fear of
wasted time it's fear of things not
going how we want them
to and that's the root of it is not that
we're actually afraid of failing because
really failing does nothing in the first
place it's what does it mean about us
it's that we would rather things be
successful and so because of that we do
what's safe and we avoid things not
going a certain way and we have to
address those we have to address what is
the root cause behind that why do we
need to feel like we're in control 24/7
of of everything why does everything
have to go our
way why does everything have to succeed
where did we come up with this belief
that I'm only going to take action if I
know 100% of the time it's going to
produce a
result and that's something that I used
to uh really struggle with and I used to
pride myself in as yet you know things
that I did always produced great result
results that I didn't waste time in my
life or my business and and that Pride
that I had that everything worked out
for
me
that you know what it was was I was
always operating inside of a framework
of what I could control now obviously
there's a level of control when it comes
to business being a business owner you
have control over things that you do and
don't do but if you're not getting sales
if you're not getting leads in your
business if you're not getting new
people in front of you and if you're not
working to close those sales all you're
doing is is operating letting everything
else outside you run you that's all
that's all that's
happening is is you're letting what
might not work out stop you from putting
yourself out there you're letting what
might not go exactly how you want it to
prevent you from the possibilities of
things going well for you and I see this
happen for people as they'll they'll
procrastinate months and months and even
years at a time not putting their
business out there not launching
something not not taking what could be
an incredible thing that impacts
people's lives changes their
income
because well what if it doesn't work
out and I would challenge you to say
well what if it does work out and maybe
you've heard that before but I want to
challenge you deeper where did that
route come from that says I demand
success and cannot accept anything
else now in the macro or in the macro
big
picture that's that's a great goal
that's awesome right I'm going to work
towards my success but realize success
is always a series of success and
failures
and that if we demand that we hit a 100
every single time you know I'm I'm
watching the baseball playoffs right now
these these players if you if
you miss the ball two out of three times
and you hit only onethird of your shots
you're an Elite baseball player you're
an elite player at that level okay so
realize that
like
we go out there in business and we think
that we got to hit 100% of our shots and
that is
so outside of the realm of
Truth you know my experience I've been
in the mentoring and coaching business
for two decades not everything that
you're going to do is going to resonate
and then we go deeper into worrying and
fear of how are people going to judge us
are they going to be disappointed are
they going to like what we've produced
are they going to resonate with it and
it stops US
from just experimenting putting
ourselves out there just seeing what
happens and the worst thing that I see
that happens is people justify it as
Integrity they justify it as wisdom they
justify it as a spirit of
Excellence that's just using clever
positive lingo to create reasons
why
you are choosing to not actually do what
works what actually works is what I've
said experimenting being willing to fail
seeing failure as a learning experience
as a lesson along the way as part of
your market
research as part of the process of
getting to where you want to
go you might say well I don't want to
pour all this energy and not produce
results where did you come up with that
belief that everything that you pour
energy into must the first time produce
the vision that you had or or or you're
going to be devastated like where did
that come
from I want you to challenge that I want
you to
challenge that that belief
system
internally
that
you're entitled
to success the first time you do
something and that if things don't work
out how you want that you somehow are a
failure and must avoid that
happening challenge
that challenge that thinking cuz that's
not a recipe for Success that is one of
the
mindsets that will prevent you from
being successful needing things to be
100% needing things to only be exactly
how you see them instead of realizing
that the process that we go through the
process of reaching our
goals has ups and downs and that the
Downs are just as important as the
ups that the things not working out are
just as relevant as the massive
successes this is the shift that most
people won't talk about that most people
avoid this is the hard part of
Entrepreneurship the hard part isn't
even doing the actual work
itself it's that we have to challenge
the fact that what if I do the work and
it doesn't work
out and still doing it
anyways and still still taking action
even if we don't know what's going to
happen
challenge the internal beliefs inside
yourself challenge those beliefs that
are
saying I can't take action unless I know
for certain it's going to work
out and and what is going on internally
where was that decision first made what
are you trying to avoid that's the real
question to ask yourself what are you
trying to avoid
happening in your life well I'm AO maybe
some people might say I don't want to
lose money on Facebook ads let me answer
that what like what like people lose
money driving to and from a job that
they hate every single day and yet we're
afraid to quote unquote lose $15 $200 on
Facebook
ads testing experimenting seeing what
happens where did that belief come in
that I can only quote unquote make an
investment if I can guarantee it's going
to work instead of it being part of the
process to actually reach our goals I've
never seen a business owner who's
successful operate with that thinking I
see a a lot of people who struggle and
never succeed with that
thinking the ones who are successful
they don't think that
way they don't
worry about is this going to work out
they do their very best to align things
in a way that will work out positively
for them but they don't not put
themselves out there out of trying to
avoid things
failing
and I think that this is one of the
biggest mental
shifts when it comes to successful
entrepreneurs when it comes to people
who struggle is
this need for things to go our
way this need for things to align with
exactly how quote unquote I see things
working out and if it doesn't I'm not
going to do it I'm not going to launch
my offer I'm not going to get leads I'm
not going to make a presentation unless
I can guarantee that it's going to
produce a result that
thinking is one of the biggest limiting
factors when it comes to your
life when it comes to your
business we cannot let that thinking get
us caught up in its web it will spin you
around and then we get caught caught up
in overthinking and overanalyzing and
then talking ourselves out of well why
you know we can make things better and
now is not the best time to be able to
put ourselves out there and all that
when when in fact you could have put
something out there experimented seen
the results analyzed it and had better
data off of a failing campaign than
trying to avoid the failure
itself that's how I see
things that's how successful business
owners see see
things that's how successful mentors and
coaches see things is they're not trying
to avoid
failure we're so focused on
experimenting trying things out seeing
what people respond to seeing what they
take action
with loving the process making
connecting with other people being the
most important part instead
of quote unquote making money producing
that result quot you know
making money and producing a result is
is very important but if that's your
main focus you're not going to put
anything out there and that's a problem
if your desire to make cash
flow is that great that you won't even
put something out there that's a
Miss misappropriated focus on things
when I talk about making sales and
marketing your most important priority
I'm talking about the fact that that's
where you need to be putting your energy
and selling and actually getting results
and actually instead of focusing so much
on client
fulfillment actually taking the time to
get new clients but if you're literally
not even doing the work to get new
clients because you're so stuck on
trying to make everything perfect and
we're afraid of failing and we don't
want things to not go our way that is an
an issue we need to address and we need
to look at what is beneath the surface
what is going on inside of us where did
that belief system come in what are we
trying to avoid
and when you start to really get clear
on those things and we start to
say I'm going to change that
behavior that is no longer how I'm going
to
operate I'm going to have an
experimentation mindset I'm going to be
willing to put myself out there even if
things don't work out perfectly that
shift will change everything for you so
you can start to make the kind of money
that you know is possible for you
because that's exactly what's happened
for me for the business owners that I
know who are successful that's exactly
how they got
there all right listen if this podcast
has helped you share it with
somebody jump onto one of our Live
Events and listen get on the waiting
list for our client growth accelerator
group mentorship program when we open
the doors to it it's one of the best
group mentorship programs out there
helping coaches mentors and trainers
scale their businesses and make six and
seven figures
online talk soon
[Music]
[Applause]
sh